Register of the Karl H. Von Wiegand papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Karl H. Von Wiegand papers
1911-1961
75092
Hoover Institution Archives
83 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 43 envelopes, memorabilia (39.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, dispatches, writings, photographs, clippings, and printed matter relating to European diplomacy and German politics between the world wars, the Sino-Japanese War, the European Theater in World War II, the Cold War, the post-war Middle Eastern situation, and American foreign policy.
Von Wiegand, Karl H.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1874 September 11 Born, Hessen, Germany
1878 Immigrated with family to the United States, settled in Iowa
1888 Naturalized as American citizen
1896 Telegraph operator, Western Union, Chicago
1902-1904 Staff member, San Francisco Examiner
1907-1910 Manager, Western Division Office, Associated Press, San Francisco
1911-1915 Correspondent, United Press Foreign staff, Berlin
1914, November Interview with Admiral Tirpitz concerning German plans for submarine warfare
1915, April 11 Interview with Pope Benedict XV concerning effort for peace
1915-1917 War correspondent, New York World
1917-1961 Foreign correspondent, Hearst Newspapers
1928 Passenger, Graf Zeppelin, first trans-Atlantic flight
1929 Passenger, Graf Zeppelin, first flight around the world
1936 Passenger, Hindenburg, trans-Atlantic flight
1940 Interview with Adolf Hitler concerning German view of the United States
1942 Interned by the Japanese
1943 Repatriated
1961 Died, Zürich, Switzerland
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, dispatches, writings, photographs, clippings, and printed matter relating to European diplomacy and German politics between the world wars, the Sino-Japanese War, the European Theater in World War II, the Cold War, the postwar Middle Eastern situation, and American foreign policy.
Aeronautics.; Air-ships.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945.; World politics.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Western Front.; Europe--History--1918-1945.; Germany--Politics and government--20th century.; Middle East--Politics and government.; Journalists.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1915-1961 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical data, memorabilia, personal records, and press reports relating to the career of Karl H. von Wiegand, arranged by subject.
  - Biographical sketches, typescripts, undated (Box 1)
  - Book collection list, typescript, undated
  - Cards, business and visiting, printed copies, undated
  - Engraving plates, undated
  - Family data, printed copies, 1926-1950
  - Financial papers, receipts, etc.
    - Undated
    - 1919-1921
    - 1922
    - 1923
    - 1924
    - 1925-1929
    - 1930s (Box 2)
    - 1940s
    - 1950s
  - Honors, printed copies, 1959
  - Identification, press cards, etc., printed and typescript copies, 1919-1951
  - Mailing list, typescript, undated
  - Medical records, printed and typescript copies, 1929-1961
  - Memorabilia, 1915-1954
    - General
    - Autograph album, 1915-1916
    - Autograph album, 1916-1920
  - Press reports relating to von Wiegand's career
    - Undated (Box 3A)
    - 1920s
    - 1930s
    - 1940s
    - 1950s
      - General
      - 1950-1955
      - 1956-1959
    - 1960s (Box 3B)
  - Residences, data relating to
    - Villa Achnaton, 1956
      Correspondence and plans, printed and typescript copies.
    - Villa Seeschloessl, 1920, 1924
      Legal papers, typescripts.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1961 (Boxes 4-23)
  Correspondence of Karl H. von Wiegand, arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Unidentified (Box 4)
  - General
  - Letters from readers
    - Undated
    - 1924-1944
    - 1945-1956
  - Greeting cards
  - Abegg, Lily (2), 1961 (Box 5)
  - Abul Fath, Mahmoud (2), 1929, 1940
  - Adenauer, Konrad (3), 1953, 1954, 1960
  - Adlon, Hotel, Berlin (5), 1922-1924
  - Agoston, Thomas (8), 1951-1960
  - Albert, H. F. (2), 1921-1922
  - Allen, Henry T. (1), 1920
  - Allen, Hugh (2), 1924-1929
  - Amer, Abdel Hakim (1), 1959
  - American Relief Administration (1), 1920
  - Anker, Kurt (2), 1924
  - Anspacher, John M. (1), 1946
  - Archibald, Jos. F. (1), 1920
  - Arnhold, Jean (Mrs. Henry) (11), 1944-1946
  - Arnold, H. H. (1), 1939
  - Ashley, Florence (1), undated
  - Arnot, Charles P., 1958-1959
  - Aziza (1), 1929
  - Bagby, P. H. (21), 1920-1922
  - Balbo, Italo (3), 1940
  - Ball, Alice (1), undated
  - Ball, Elmer, J. (8), 1945-1946
  - Ball, "Jimmy" (2), 1947
  - Balluseck, D. J. von (5), 1939-1940
  - Balser, Marie (1), 1932
  - Bammel, Heinrich (1), 1921
  - Barry, Robert (2), 1931
  - Barthelme (2), 1922
  - Bartlett, George (1), 1946
  - Baskervill, W. M. (1), 1951
  - Bauer, Ernst (5), 1925-1948
  - Bauer, Max (65), 1920-1928
    Presumably identical with Dr. B. and Dr. Becker. See also: Luise Engeler.
  - Baumbach, Werner (5), 1949-1952
  - Becker, Anneliese (1), 1952
  - Beese-Bontard, Melli (3), 1919
  - Behn, Fritz (1), 1953
  - Bentinek, Graf (1), 1921
  - Berchtold, [Leopold, Graf] (3), 1919
  - Berg, F[riedrich] von (10), 1919-1921
  - Berkson, Eleanor (1), 1959
  - Berkson, Seymour (62), 1935-1958
  - Berle, A. A., Jr. (1), 1927
  - Berlin, Richard (308), 1936-1961
    - Undated
    - 1936-1949
    - 1952-1955 (Box 6)
    - 1956-1957
    - 1958-1959
    - 1960-1961
  - Berliner Lokal-Anzeiger (7), 1922-1929
  - Berliner Tageblatt (4), 1923-1924
  - Berliner Volks-Zeitung (1), 1924
  - Bernhardi, Friedrich von (19), 1919-1920
  - Bernstorff, [Johann-Heinrich, Graf] (17), 1919-1935
  - Bertelli, Charles F. (63), 1921-1925
  - Berti, Louis (1), 1955
  - Bess, Demaree C. (2), 1927-1929
  - Bettmann Hollweg, [Theobald von] (1), 1919
    See also: Heilbron
  - Bilainkin, George (1), 1956
  - "Bill," incomplete identification (6), 1929-1956
  - Bing, Ede (2), 1922 (Box 7)
  - Blackwell, F. (1), 1922
  - Blaker, W. F. (4), 1927-1928
  - Bleibtreu, William (1), 1949
  - Block, Victor J. (2), 1921
  - Bloem, Walter (5), 1921-1922
  - Blomberg, [Werner] (1), 1936
  - Blood, Leighton (9), 1924
  - Blumenthal, Ike (1), undated
  - Bock, Wilhelm (1), 1946
  - Bosdari, Comte (2), 1924
  - Boskovitz, K. M. (6), 1954
  - Boess (3), 1922
  - Bosshard, Walter (18), 1931-1958
  - La bourse egyptienne (2), 1953
  - Bouton, S. Miles (1), 1920
  - Bouve, Clement L. (1), 1919
  - Boy-Ed, Karl (17), 1919-1921
  - Brada, George (1), 1953
  - Bradley, William Aspenwall, Mrs. (3), 1940
  - Brandt & Brandt (1), 1936
  - Brauchitsch, [Walter] (2), 1940
  - Brauer, Juli (1), 1919
  - Breitscheid, [Rudolf] (1), 1920
  - Breucker, Wilhelm (1), 1951
  - Brookins, Arthur C. (3), 1946
  - Brown, George Rothwell (1), 1944
  - Bruchman, R. C. (2), 1921
  - Brutus, Lee N. (2), 1940, 1948
  - Bryant (1), 1921
  - Budszus, Andrew (1), 1956
  - Burton, Harry P. (6), 1939-1944
  - Buss, Claude A. (21), 1944-1946
  - Buttikofer, T. J. (1), 1944
  - Byam, Wallace (3), 1945
  - Cassidy, Henry (2), 1959
  - Cecilie, Kronprinzessin (1), 1919
  - Chamberlain, Jessie R. (4), 1946-1947
  - Chiang, Kai-shek (3), 1932
  - Chicherin, [Georgii] (3), 1921-1925
  - Child, Richard (1), 1922
  - Chinigo, Michael (29), 1944-1957
  - Clifford, Eddy (32), 1947-1959
  - Coblentz, E. D. (32), 1940-1959
  - Colson, Everett A. (1), 1935
  - Conniff, Frank (2), 1954-1955
  - Connolly, John F., S. J. (3), 1945
  - Connolly, J. V. (143), 1930-1945
  - Consodine, "Bob" (2), 1959
  - Constantine, King of Greece [See: Greece, Press Bureau]
  - Cooke, G. P. (5), 1946-1947
  - Cooper, Lindsey T. (1), 1945
  - Cosmopolitan (1), 1936
  - Coste, Brutus (5), 1946-1948 (Box 8)
  - Cotta'sche Buchhandlung Nachfolger (3), 1924
  - Criewitz (2), 1936
  - Crosby, O. T. (1), 1922
  - Curley, Mary Grace (8), 1953-1956
  - Curley, William A. (52), 1940-1955
  - Darviche, Lydia [See: Lydia Oswald]
  - Daufeldt, Hedwig Gut (2), 1946-1947
  - David, Edith (2), 1928
  - Davies, Marion (4), 1931-1951
  - Davis, Nathaniel P. (1), 1944
  - Day, Donald (6), 1921, 1953
  - DeCourcey, Geraldine (4), 1946
  - Delany, Gerald C. (1), 1923
  - Delbrueck, [Hans] (2), 1919-1925
  - Dell, Robert (1), 1924
  - Dessouki, Salah (5), 1961
  - Deutelmoser, Erhard (2), 1954
  - Deutsche Allgemeine Correspondenz (1), 1921
  - Deutsche Verlagsgesellschaft (1), 1920
  - Devin-Adair, Company, 1951-1952
  - De Zirkoff, Boris (1), 1947
  - Diano, N. (1), 1946
  - Diarios de Noticias, Lisbon (1), 1940
  - Dillon, Vivian (3), 1921
  - Dodd, William E. (1), 1935
  - Dombrowski, Erich (1), 1950
  - Dommes, [Wilhelm] von (4), 1921
  - Donald, W. H. (4), 1932-1938
  - Dornier, [Claude] (3), 1928-1929
  - Dosch-Fleurot, Arno (10), 1944-1949
  - Doubleday, Doran & Company (1), 1935
  - Downs, Kenneth (2), 1940
  - Dresel, Ellis Loring (12), 1920-1922
  - Dresser & Escher (37), 1936-1945
  - Drummond-Hay, Grace M. Hay (611), 1925-1945
    - Undated
    - 1925
    - 1926
    - 1927
    - 1928
    - 1929
    - 1930 (Box 9)
    - 1931
    - 1932
    - 1933
    - 1934
    - 1935
    - 1935
    - 1937
    - 1938
    - 1939 (Box 10)
    - 1940
      - January - February
      - March - December
    - 1941
    - 1942
    - 1943
    - 1944
    - 1945
  - Drummond-Hay, H. R. (3), 1946
  - Dulles, John Foster (10), 1949-1954 (Box 11)
  - Duerer-Verlag, Buenos Aires (1), 1951
  - Earle, George H. (20), 1960
  - Ebert, Friedrich (1), 1924
  - Eble Frank X. A. (2), 1924
  - Eckener, Hugo (31), 1924-1948
  - Einwohnerwehr, Niederpoecking (1), 1920
  - Enderis, Guido (4), 1944-1945
  - Engeler, Luise (8), 1924-1948
  - Enver, Pasha (2), 1920
  - Erzberger, [Mattias] (3), 1920
  - Escherich, Georg (1), 1923
  - Esser, Joachim (3), 1947-1948
  - Eucken, Rudolf (1), 1925
  - Fahrmbacher, W. (7), 1958-1959
  - Falkenhausen, [Alexander von] (4), 1954
  - Falkenhayn, [Erich von] (2), 1921
  - Faris, Barry (3), 1940-1944
  - Feigl, Carl (1), 1930
  - Feng, C. T. (1), 1928
  - Ferguson, Homer (1), 1946
  - Ferrera, Orestes (1), 1946
  - Fessmann (1), 1935
  - Filsinger, Ernst (1), 1922
  - Finke, August (1), 1951
  - Fischer, Martin (4), 1954
  - Flick-Steger, Carl (446), 1931-1961
    Also known as Charles L. Flick
    - Undated
    - 1930s-1940s
    - 1954
    - 1955
    - 1956
    - 1957
    - 1958
    - 1959
    - 1960 (Box 12)
    - 1961
  - Ford, Henry (3), 1920-1921
  - Ford, M. C. (10), 1943-1956
    Presumably identical with Hank, Henry, Henrico
  - Forster, Paul (1), 1940
  - Francis, Lyda Mae (1), 1953
  - "Franco," incomplete identification (1), 1939
  - Frank, K. G. (2), 1920
  - Freeman, Charmion von Wiegand (99), 1924-1960
  - Freeman, Joseph (10), 1940-1960
  - "Fritz," incomplete identification (3), 1947-1948
  - Fuchs, Otfried (2), 1929
  - Fuller, J. F. C. (5), 1949
  - Galli, Domenico (3), 1945
  - Garland, William May (3), 1945
  - Gemmingen, Baron von (4), 1919-1920
  - Gentzer, Kurt (1), 1920
  - Germany. Auswaertiges Amt (16), 1920, 1924
  - Germany. Reichspostministerium (4), 1919-1924
  - Germany. Reichspressestelle (4), 1940
  - Germany. Reichswehrministerium (4), 1919-1922
  - Germany, West. Presse- und Informationsamt (9), 1950-1954
  - Gervasi, Frank (2), 1940
  - Ghali, Wacyf Boutros, Pasha (2), 1928
  - Giannini, Vera (4), 1947
  - Gibson, Hugh (4), 1945-1950
  - Giese (1), 1925
  - Giesenkirchen, Joseph (1), 1947
  - Gifford, Woody, Carter & Hays (38), 1944-1956
  - Glassford, William (11), 1940
  - Gleason, William, Mrs. (89), 1940-1958 (Box 13)
  - Glimph, Ellinor (1), 1956
  - Goelzer, Ludwig (1), 1952
  - Goette, John, 1927-1946
  - Goodman (2), 1944
  - Gorky, M. Andreeva (1), 1922
  - Gortatowsky, J. D. (51), 1944-1954
  - Gothein, [Georg] (1), 1922
  - Gould, Randall (3), 1927-1931
  - Graveure, Eleanor Painter (11), 1922-1929
  - Graveure, Louis (3), 1922-1923
  - Greece. Minister of Foreign Affairs (1), 1957
  - Greece. Press Bureau (4), 1921
  - Greene, Marc T. (40), 1944-1947
  - Grew, Joseph C. (7), 1944
  - Grigoriu, Scarlat (1), undated
  - Gruenther, Alfred M. (3), 1952
  - Grunenberg, Karl (1), 1946
  - Grueter, W. (4), 1957-1958
  - Guck, Homer (2), 1940
  - Gudenus, Erwin (3), 1925
  - Guderian, Heinz Wilhelm (2), 1953
  - Gullino, Cesaret (7), 1945-1947
  - Habicht, H. R. (5), 1922-1924
  - Habsburg, Otto von (1), undated
  - Haecher, V. (1), 1925
  - Halder, Franz (21), 1953-1961
  - Halder, Gertrud (1), 1947
  - Hamburg-Amerika Linie (5), 1919-1924
  - Haniel (1), 1920
  - Hanfstaengl, Ernst F. Sedgwick (6), 1924-1948
  - Hanighen, Frank C. (1), 1950
  - Hansen, Gottfried (1), 1951
  - Hapgood, Norman (3), 1919-1924
  - Harden, Maximilian (36), 1919-1924
  - Harden, Maximiliane (1), undated
  - Hare, Raymond A. (1), 1957
  - Hargreaves, George T. (5), 1919-1933 (Box 14)
  - Harnack, Adolf von (1), 1925
  - Hart, Merwin K. (3), 1948
  - Hauptmann, Gerhart (1), 1925
  - Hawley, Hudson R. (2), 1955
  - Hay, Marlen (1), 1925
  - Hays, Arthur Garfield (1), 1921
  - Hearst, John R., 1931-1948
  - Hearst, William Randolph (119), 1921-1948
  - Hearst, William Randolph, Jr. (23), 1946-1959
  - Hearst Newspapers (4), 1944-1955
  - Heilbron (5), 1919-1920
  - Heineken, Ph., 1919-1924
  - Helfferich, [Karl] (1), 1919
  - Hemmer (1), 1920
  - Henius, Frank (1), undated
  - Henningsen, A. B. (2), 1944
  - Heusinger, [Ernst Adolf] (1), 1961
  - Heusler, Karl (1), 1953
  - Heuss, Theodor (1), 1953
  - Hill, David Jayne (2), 1921
  - Hillman, William (49), 1929-1940
  - Hindenburg, [Paul von] (10), 1919-1921
  - Hirscht, Helene (1), 1953
  - Hobbs (1), undated
  - Hoeck, James (1), undated
  - Hoefler, L. M. (1), 1921
  - Hoffmann und Camp Verlag (1), 1947
  - Hohenlohe, Alexander, Prinz von (1), 1922
  - Hope, Chester R. (96), 1923-1928
  - Horcher (3), 1948-1955
  - Houghton, A. (5), 1922-1925
  - Hoyt, Lansing (1), 1932
  - Howard, Roy W. (8), 1939-1944
  - Hsia, L. H. (3), 1919
  - Hsu, Chen (1), 1931
  - Humann, Hans (18), 1919-1924
  - Hunt, Frazier (1), 1923
  - Huss, [Pierre] (2), 1940
  - [Huston], Luther (1), 1927
  - India, Government of. Home Office (1), 1927
  - Ingalls, Laura (2), 1946
  - Irving Trust (149), 1929-1956
  - Isenburg, Berta von (20), 1922-1924 (Box 15)
  - Insenburg, Karl von (2), 1919-1920
  - Jaedicke (2), 1924
  - Jagow, Gottlieb von (13), 1919-1920
  - Jeritza, Maria (2), 1922
  - Jessurun, J. (8), 1939-1940
  - "Joan," incomplete identification (1), 1932
  - Johnson, Hiram (1), 1924
  - Johnson, Ned B. (18), 1940-1947
  - Johnston, Hattie Belle (5), 1953-1960
  - Johnston, William (1), 1919
  - Jordon, Max Arthur (46), 1922-1952
  - Jungheim (2), 1919-1920
  - Junkers, Hugo (1), 1925
  - Kahr, [Gustav, Ritter von] (3), 1921
  - Kaltenborn, Hans V. (5), 1959-1960
  - Kaufmann, Albert A. (2), 1922-1923
  - Kellermann, Bernhard (1), 1921
  - Kemaj, Leon (17), 1948-1955
  - Kempner, [Franz] (1), 1925
  - Kent, Frank R. (1), undated
  - Kerr, Caroline V. (4), 1922-1923
  - Kfoury, Henry (2), 1957
  - Khrushchev, Nikita (1), 1958
  - Kiewitz, Werner von (1), 1959
  - King, William H. (4), 1924
  - Kingsbury-Smith, Joseph (52), 1946-1961
  - Kingson, Iown (4), 1946
  - Kinney, Henry W. (4), 1946
  - Klagges, Reinar (2), 1951
  - Klein, Ernst (1), 1949
  - Klein, James (2), 1924
  - Kleinmichel (3), 1921
  - Kliefoth, Louis (1), 1922
  - Klitzsch, Ludwig (1), 1924
  - Kluge, Magda (9), 1920-1922
  - Knickerbocker, Hubert R. (2), 1927
  - Knickerbocker, Laura Patrick (5), 1927
  - Knisely, Burton (1), 1923
  - Knoblaugh, H. Edward (16), 1946-1953
  - Knox, Frank (73), 1928-1935
  - Koch, Hans (4), 1953-1954
  - Koehler Verlag (14), 1919-1922, 1958
  - Koenig, Anna May (1), 1925
  - Koenig, Leo (2), 1924
  - Koenigsberg, M. (16), 1920-1927
  - Komura, K. (2), 1927 (Box 16)
  - Koninklijke Luchtvaart Maatschappij (5), 1934
  - Kontorowitch, A. (1), 1927
  - Koo, V. K. Wellington (2), undated
  - Kordt, Erich (3), 1947-1950
  - Kriebel, H[ermann] (4), 1920-1929
  - Kroeger, Otto G. (20), 1920-1925
  - Kuehn, Joachim (1), 1924
  - Kunert, Ernst G. (2), 1924
  - Kunwald, Gottfried (2), 1924
  - Kurzer, Joseph (1), 1924
  - Lachman (1), 1924
  - LaGro, J. L. (1), 1947
  - Lal, Gobind Behari (2), 1944
  - Landone, Brown (2), 1944
  - Lang, Anton (5), 1922-1923
  - Langen, Paul (1), 1950
  - Larisch, Friedrich (2), 1924
  - Larisch, Maria (7), 1924
  - Lee, John E. (2), 1957
  - Lee, P. H. (1), 1929
  - Leeds, Stanton B. (17), 1937-1951
  - Leeds, William (1), 1929
  - Lehar (14), 1924-1926
  - Lehar, Franz (6), 1921-1924
  - Lenkeit, Margarethe (2), 1920-1921
  - Lepsius, Ernst R. (2), 1924
  - Lerchenfeld (6), 1922
  - Lethbridge, Grace E. (4), 1945-1946
  - Leuenberger, Hans (49), 1947-1951
  - Levald, M. (2), 1924
  - Levante, Valencia (2), undated
  - Levine, Isaac, "Don" (4), 1922-1924
  - Lewis & Lewis (3), 1944-1948
  - Li Nai (2), 1929
  - Licudi, Hector (3), 1945-1946
  - Lincoln, C. M. (1), 1920
  - Litvinov, [Maxim] (1), 1922
  - Lloyd George, David (1), 1922
  - Lochner, Louis (6), 1949-1959
  - Lockhart, Frank (1), 1944
  - Loebe, [Paul] (1), 1925
  - Loesch, Heinrich von (4), 1956-1957
  - Long, Ray (12), 1924-1925
  - Loring, John (2), 1944
  - Lovett, Leland F. (3), 1944
  - Loy, Wilhelm (1), 1947
  - Ludendorff, [Erich] (1), 1931
  - Ludwig, Emil (1), 1921
  - Luftschiffbau Zeppelin (5), 1924-1929
  - Lustie, Alvin (2), 1929, 1932
  - Lynch, Arthur (3), 1921
  - MacNamara, Paul (1), 1944
  - Mahmoud, Mohamed (3), 1940
  - Makaruschka, L. (1), 1955
  - Maltzan, Ago von (10), 1921-1924
  - Manchester Guardian (3), 1923
  - Marconi Radio Telegraph Company, Egypt (3), 1947-1948
  - Marcovic, Miveille (1), 1944
  - Martin, Richard (1), 1946
  - Marx, Wilhelm (1), 1924
  - Mason, Ellen (5), 1948/1957
  - Mason, Frank (150), 1921-1957
  - Massary, "Fritzi" (2), 1921 (Box 17)
  - Matsuoka, Yosuke (19), 1930-1941
  - Matuschke, Ella (2), 1919
  - Matzky (3), 1954-1955
  - McCabe, Alexander (2), 1950
  - McCauley & Henry (2), 1945-1950
  - McClatchy, Charles K. (9), 1920-1924
  - McCloy, John J. (5), 1949-1951
  - McClure, Brooks (1), 1957
  - McDonnell, P. G. (1), 1922
  - McLaughlin, Charles (9), 1947-1956
  - McQueen, U. G., Mrs. (1), 1946
  - Mealand, [Richard] (1), 1936
  - Mehnert, Klaus (8), 1946-1959
  - Meigs, M. C. (5), 1945
  - Meister, F. W. von (33), 1929-1955
  - Melzer, Alfons (2), 1921
  - Merrill, Bradford (7), 1920-1927
  - Merrill, Pearl (18), 1944-1958
  - "Mickey," incomplete identification (3), 1940-1947
  - Middleton, William (34), 1945-1949
  - Midzutani, S. (2), 1929
  - Miller, Cha[rle]s W. (2), 1924
  - Mills, James (1), undated
  - Mitschke, Ernst Marcel (1), 1923
  - Mittler & Sohn (3), 1919-1921
  - Mogk, E. (2), 1947-1948
  - Mohr, W. H. (2), 1951
  - Mohr, Wilhelmine (7), 1924
  - Mohyeddin, Zakavia (1), 1957
  - Moltke, [Helmuth von] (1), 1924
  - Montgelas, Albrecht (1), undated
  - Montgomery de Pourtales, Laura (1), 1924
  - Moore, J. A. (1), 1924
  - Moral (2), 1937
  - Muenchner neuste Nachrichten (2), 1924
  - Mydans, Carl (2), 1944
  - Naebat, H. (1), 1936
  - Naguib, Mohamed (4), 1953
  - Nahas, Mustapha (1), undated
  - Nasser, Gamel Abdel (10), 1953-1959
  - Naumann, Viktor (3), 1921
  - Negri, Pola (1), 1920
  - Neurath, [Konstantin] von (2), 1925
  - Newcombe, W. A. (5), 1923
  - Newell, Isac, Mrs. (2), 1944
  - Neymann, Clarence A. (4), 1947
  - "Nico," incomplete identification (2), 1927
  - Nicolai (1), 1922
  - Nomura, K. (2), 1939
  - Norddeutscher Lloyd (3), 1920, 1935
  - Noske, G[ustav] (4), 1920-1921
  - Nourse, James R. (1), 1927
  - Nowak, Karl Friedrich (3), 1924
  - O'Brien, Frederick (1), 1923
  - Oestreicher, J. D. (3), 1940, 1946
  - Ohain, Papst von (1), 1920
  - O'Neill, J. J. (1), 1922
  - Ormerod, C. B. (17), 1944-1945
  - Oschmann (1), 1919
  - Ostasiatischer Verein (1), 1951 (Box 18)
  - Oswald, Lydia (100), 1947-1954
  - Otte, Viktor (11), 1924
  - Otto, Wilhelm (12), 1924
  - Pabst, Waldemar (14), 1947-1950
  - Painter, Eleanor [See: Graveure, Eleanor Painter]
  - Papen, Franz von (13), 1922-1933
  - Patent Exploitation Company (1), 1931
  - "Paula," incomplete identification (4), 1947-1948
  - Pease, Theodore (1), 1945
  - Pegler, Westbrook (5), 1959
  - Peralta, Laura (1), undated
  - Perry, John H. (1), 1923
  - "Pete," incomplete identification (6), 1940
  - Pew, Marlen (2), 1920
  - Phibbs, J. Pullar (1), 1936
  - Polachek, Victor (3), 1927
  - Popoff, George K. (1), 1921
  - Prellwitz, Juergen von (82), 1947-1957
  - Prellwitz, Karin von (7), 1949-1953
  - Pressburger, Bedrich (2), 1946
  - Preuss, Hugo (1), 1925
  - Prew, Robert J. (19), 1920-1924
  - Price, Ward (15), 1920, 1946-1960
  - Procapi, J. (3), 1944
  - Pruss, Max (2), 1946
  - Pugsley, Kittie (4), 1945-1946
  - Puttkamer, Renate von (2), 1947
  - Quidde (1), 1919
  - Quo, Tai-chi (2), undated
  - Raabe, A. (1), 1947
  - Rachmann, S. (7), 1924
  - Radek, Karl (2), 1922
  - Raeder (2), 1940
  - Ranck, T. V. (38), 1928-1929 (Box 19)
  - Rathenau, Walther (1), 1922
  - Rauderbaugh, W. B. (1), 1945
  - Rechberg, Arnold (2), 1920
  - Reed, William (1), 1933
  - Reichenau, Alis von (6), 1947-1948
  - Reinhard, Max (1), 1922
  - Remmington, Marion (2), 1946
  - Reswick (2), 1924
  - Rheinbaben (3), 1919-1920
  - Richards, Guy (1), 1956
  - Richards, Ray (36), 1944-1948
  - Ridder, Bernard H. (2), 1919/1921
  - Riis, S. M. (1), 1944
  - Ritchie, Robert (7), 1924-1929
  - Roediger (2), 1920
  - Rohrbach, Paul (7), 1920, 1948-1949
  - Rosen, [Friedrich] (2), undated
  - Rosendahl, C. E. (10), 1929-1959
  - Rupprecht, Kronprinz (1), 1921
  - Rustem, A. (2), undated
  - Sabarth, Mary (1), 1929
  - Sachse, Charlotte (1), 1924
  - Said, Boris (1), 1926
  - Salah El-Din (2), 1951
  - Salzmann, Erich von (2), 1923, 1928
  - San Francisco Examiner (3), 1959
  - "Sandy," incomplete identification (1), undated
  - Sassoon, Phillip (2), 1922
  - Saunders, M. (2), 1927
  - Scelba, Mario (1), 1954
  - Schacht, Hjalmar (4), 1948, 1959
  - Schager-Eckertsau (2), 1922
  - Scharrer (1), 1923
  - Schedelmann, Anton (2), 1924
  - Schedelmann, Hans (2), 1927
  - Scheer (1), 1921
  - Scheffer, Paul (1), 1959
  - Scheibe, A. (4), 1924
  - Schelking, L. von (1), 1921
  - Schenck, Karl (1), 1922
  - Schenke, Wolf (1), 1948
  - Scheubner-Richter, [Max Erwin von] (3), 1922-1923
  - Schilinsky, Adolf (2), 1924
  - Schiller, Hans von (1), 1956
  - Schilling (1), 1921
  - Schirmer, Hans H. (1), 1956
  - Schlund, Herman (1), 1944
  - Schmidt-Pauli, Edgar von (4), 1948-1955
  - Schmitz, Ernest (1), 1951
  - Schneider, Herbert (4), 1924
  - Schnell, Eduard (1), 1927
  - Schoppe, Axel (1), 1920
  - Schreiner, George A. (9), 1919-1928
  - Schuette, Oswald, F. (2), 1921, 1924
  - Schuler, Maria (1), 1938
  - Schumm, H. G. W. (14), 1945-1957
  - Schuschnigg, Walter von (2), 1945
  - Schusser, German (1), 1953
  - Schutzbar-Milchling, Margot von (18), 1940, 1945-1953 (Box 20)
  - Schwarz van Berk, Hans (3), 1951
  - Schwarzenburg, C. (1), 1953
  - Schwormstaedt, Felix (2), 1924
  - Seabridge, G. W. (6), 1940, 1945
  - Seeberg, Axel (7), 1959
  - Seeckt, Hans von (1), 1920
  - Selassie, Haile (1), 1936
  - Seymour, Charles (3), 1928
  - Shaker, Amin (8), 1952-1955
  - Sharp, Clifford (5), 1924
  - Sheehan, Eastman (3), 1939-1945